Ladies and gentlemen.
what you're about to witness
is the next evolution
in military engagement.
A machine that operates
with surgical precision.
And in a world
where every action
is under the media microscope.
this technology
will allow our nation
and its allies the means
to act quickly. decisively
and without the specter
of political blowback.
Madam Secretary.
glad you could join us.
Would you mind explaining to
me why you're conducting
a joint military operation
without my approval?
I appreciate
it looks like that. Shelly.
but we're here strictly
as technical support.
The mission's being conducted
by Saudi intelligence.
We're merely loaning out
the asset.
What are you talking about?
What asset?
Eyes are up.
What you just saw
was not only a test
of our technological prowess
but a clear message
to our enemies.
If the 21st century wants
another arms race.
you better goddamn believe
we intend to win it.
What the hell
was that?
She just shot Tripathi.
- Someone get her on the comms.
- She's not responding.
What the hell is going on.
Sattler? Are we being hacked?
Everybody. stay calm! Okay?
One of you. shut this down.
We can't.
We don't have control.
Well. then who the hell does?
Jesus.
You are in violation
of your orders. Amelia.
Confirm your objective.
But that would spoil
the surprise.
Before we start.
I want you to know
that nothing you say here
will get your aunt
in any trouble.
I'm no longer here
by order of the court.
I just wanted to check in
and see how you're doing.
given everything
that's happened.
I mean…
I guess it could've been
a lot worse.
A live launch for a new toy
has devolved
into a murderous rampage.
Toy designer Gemma Forrester
appeared
in a Seattle
district court today
facing charges of
reckless endangerment.
A lot of people blame
Gemma for what M3gan did.
For a long time.
she blamed herself.
But the more she went on TV
to talk about what happened.
the more she realized
she had an opportunity
to turn it into
something positive.
This is about
a world in crisis
Outsourcing our parental
duties to devices.
plowing our kids' minds
with electronically charged
dopamine hits.
You wouldn't give
your child cocaine.
Why would you give them
a smartphone?
And that's
how she met Christian.
- Hi. Gemma? Hi.
- Yeah?
Uh. Christian Bradley.
He runs a foundation
that warns people
about the dangers of Al.
They try to convince
politicians here
and around the world
to make safer laws around it
so that what happened with
M3gan doesn't happen again.
Gemma still believes technology
can be used for good.
Just that kids shouldn't spend
so much time around it.
But she always makes a point
of explaining the reasons why.
"And so. as it turned out.
companies were
"using Section 230
as a way to skirt the law
"and monetize the attention
of children
"with no regard
for their mental health."
And how do you
feel about that?
I think not being on a device
frees you up
to try other things.
Helps you make new friends.
Thanks to your
dork mom.
we just had our phones
taken off of us.
Guess I'll have to find
other ways to amuse myself.
And you know
what else?
You're not gonna have
that weird.
janky doll to protect you.
I guess you're right.
But let me ask you this.
Sapphire.
Who's protecting you?
Oh. so you think
you're tough?
I sent you to aikido
because it is
the least aggressive form
of martial arts.
And we've talked
about the merits
of using Steven Seagal
as a role model.
I'm not saying
we don't have our problems.
but the important thing
is that we get
through them together.
Just like we said we would
So. after
what happened with M3gan.
our team went through something
of a philosophical shift.
And while Gemma
has obviously become
a strong voice for regulation.
our company is still very much
focused on innovation
but with a specific view toward
socially conscious products
that move humanity
in the right direction.
So. with that in mind.
I'd like to present to you
our flagship invention.
The Exoskeletor Model 1
- Cole. this is Niles Keller.
- I know.
You want to come say hi?
I want to come
and say hi. Yes.
Can you… Yeah. Tess.
just come here for a second.
Excuse me.
What's happening?
It's frozen.
When you walked out. it froze.
I cannot get
my body to move.
Okay. Just. uh…
I'm gonna reboot.
No. no. no.
Tess. you don't understand.
- I have to use the bathroom.
- No. No. no. no. no. no. no.
- Both.
- No!
We've already wasted his time
waiting for Gemma.
We have ten minutes
to turn this around.
We're not gonna make it.
We're gonna make it.
Why don't you just
take the shortcut?
'Cause I don't need an algorithm
to tell me how to drive. okay?
Oh. Whoa.
'Kay.
There we go.
That feels better.
So. I'm walking over.
as you can see.
So. we see the suit
as a real game changer.
Not only in helping those
with limited function
but also in addressing
occupational overuse syndrome
for laborers.
factory workers.
Right. In the next
five years. they say
half the industrial sector's
in danger
of losing their job to robots
because machines
never experience fatigue.
But what if the same
could be said for us?
Right now. I'm only using 20%
of my body's muscular function.
And if that's too much.
well. I could always take
a quick siesta.
So our hope is you don't have
to fear a robot revolution
when you can compete with it.
That sounds like
a pretty good tagline.
- So. how does it work?
- Well. uh.
the suit has its own internal
myoelectric receptors
that respond
to each muscle contraction.
So sorry I'm late…
I told you we needed
to stress-test the sensors.
You know what
would have been great?
If you had
actually been here.
I thought by having
the lab in your house.
it'd be a lot harder
to show up late.
and yet somehow
you managed it.
Cole's right. I mean. I don't
want to get in the way
of the work you're doing
at the foundation.
but the reality is you are
stretched pretty thin.
Okay. can we just not do this
in front of my niece. please?
Cady. do you think it's possible
you could be somewhere else?
Yeah. but you should
come look at this.
- I think you were hacked.
- What?
Oh. Jesus.
she's right.
There are stray commands
all over the source code.
We haven't even gone public
with this yet.
I mean. who would want
to do that?
Knock-knock.
Pardon my interruption.
- Holy shit.
- Alton Appleton.
Hi. Sorry.
No. no. that's okay.
Gemma. I hope you don't mind
me popping in unannounced.
Alton. To what do we owe
this unexpected pleasure?
It sounds like
there was a slight snag
with your demonstration.
Yeah. well. we got hacked.
but you wouldn't know
anything about that. right?
Gemma. why would a man
of my standing
need to resort
to such tactics?
The real question is:
Why have you contacted
every philanthro-capitalist
in the Western world
to invest in your product
but me?
I think you can
figure that out
- You know what I think?
- Hmm?
I think you see me as this
high-functioning billionaire
with multiple PhDs
and you're threatened by it.
What you don't see is a man
who can't stand to see
someone with your talent
slumming it in some…
excuse me…
converted crack house.
Wow. I really appreciate
your concern.
We're not taking
outside offers…
Sorry. Gemma. One moment.
Murray. you still in Monaco?
You look like
you haven't slept.
Oh. no. Oh. no.
Yeah. I've seen them.
Uh. I still think they're too close
to Aston Martin's design.
No. I've got them
on-screen now.
Ugh. hate it.
It's awful.
I've just zoomed in.
and I hate it even more.
Uh. listen.
I'm with someone.
No. not in that way.
Although…
I just sent you a photo.
We'll talk about it
trackside. yeah?
Okay. Ta-ta. Go.
As I was saying. we really
appreciate you stopping by.
Listen. I don't have
much time.
so I'm going to cut
to the chase.
Any device that relies
on muscle signals
is going to suffer
from latency.
It's clumsy.
To take this to the next level.
you're going to need
a direct
cerebral interface.
You're going to need
my neural chip.
Alton. you know
where I stand on this
We are not gonna be
part of a company
that turns people
into cyborgs.
You conducted a clinical trial
that resulted in
30% of the test subjects
being hospitalized.
Well. at least I didn't use
my own niece as a guinea pig.
The important thing is
now we have a product
that works.
Based on what?
I haven't seen a single
piece of data that shows
it does anything other than
help you make a phone call.
Whoa.
Look. I understand
your reservations.
but you can either spend
the rest of your life
trying to fight the future or
you can help us to shape it.
I hope you do
the latter.
I'm not interested.
Well. you may want to discuss
that with your colleagues.
Listen. it's our company's
25th anniversary tomorrow.
Why don't you see
what we're all about
before you make any decisions?
Alton.
No one is denying the power
this technology has.
but if you put an Al
inside a human brain.
it is not gonna ride shotgun.
Hey.
Breaking news tonight.
Alton Appleton
takes one step for man
and one giant leap
for his company's share price.
Also tonight.
the Senate votes in favor
of an Al regulation bill.
which the president is hailing
as a bipartisan victory.
but what does it mean
for the tech industry?
It means nothing.
They took our proposal.
and they neutered it.
There's not a single
actionable law in here
that would force anyone
to behave any differently.
Your impatience in the
political process is adorable.
Listen. change doesn't come from Washington.
It comes to Washington.
If this meeting with the Chinese
ambassador goes well.
they have no choice
but to pay attention.
Cady. what are you doing?
I'm trying to update
Elsie's operating system
to the smart home.
You want to know why
it's not updating?
Because Alton Appleton wants
you to buy a brand-new one.
Christian's right.
And also. I don't need Elsie
- to open a drawer for me.
- Certainly. Gemma.
Before you ask.
that was not my idea.
It came with the house.
I'm just trying to figure out how
you can afford a place like this.
given that we both work
for a nonprofit.
Well. because it was
obscenely cheap.
I think the landlord must be
using it to launder money.
I think the landlord
might like you.
Uh. Cady?
How's. un… how's the
new school treating you?
- Are you settling in okay?
- Yeah. it's awesome.
Oh. nice.
What's your. uh… what's
your favorite subject?
Computer science.
Oh
so. you re gonna follow
in your aunt's footsteps?
That's still up
for discussion.
She's actually
a really good soccer player.
Yeah. but I'm not gonna make
a career out of it.
Well. you could get
a scholarship.
and then you could decide
what you want to do.
I already have decided
Well. I think
it's pretty cool.
- You do?
- Yes.
Look. I'm not against
technology.
I spent 15 years
in cybersecurity.
I think we need smart kids
like you running things.
Otherwise. we're gonna end up
with paper clips.
- What?
- Paper clips.
It's how we used to joke about
instrumental convergence
in college.
The theory is that
if you asked an Al
to make as many paper clips
as possible.
it would destroy
the whole world to do it.
Kind of like
what happened with M3gan.
In what way?
Well. as complex
an operating system
as M3gan was.
she was just a machine trying
to achieve an objective.
So any time
she made any kind
of emotional connection
with you.
it was just a bunch
of ones and zeros
working to satisfy
a reward function.
Which. in of itself.
was a terrible thing
I mean. thank God
you stopped her when you did
I mean. who knows
what would've happened?
There will always be
forces in this world
that wish to cause us harm.
But I want you to know
that I won't let that happen.
I won't let anything
harm you ever again.
Hey.
Come on.
After everything
we've been through.
are we really keeping secrets
from each other?
Cady.
You don't have to hide
things like this from me.
I forget how hard it must be for
you not to have them around.
But I haven't forgotten
the promise I made to her.
That I will protect you.
You mean that
you'd be there.
Hmm?
The promise you made
is that you'd be there.
and you are.
Don't touch that remote.
We're trying to get
your attention.
You're in grave danger.
You must leave at once.
911. What's your emergency?
There's someone trying
to break into my house.
So what
you gonna do about it?
- What?
- I said stop acting like a little girl
and handle it.
Your niece is upstairs.
and you want to wait
for the police to get here?
She'll be dead before they get
to the front door.
- No.
- Yes. it's me.
What a shock. et cetera.
We both know you have
bigger problems right now.
- What's going on?
- Get upstairs.
- The hell are you doing?
- They're not here.
- Of course they're here.
- Who cares?
Why don't we just
get the laptop?
I'm telling you.
they're here.
And they know
we are. too.
Ms. Forrester.
What do you say you come out
of there and we'll…
Let go of the girl!
Put the weapon down!
You've reached 911.
What's your emergency?
Yes. Hi.
We are at 16 Mayoral Drive.
Wait. please!
Ms. Forrester.
don't call the authorities.
We are the authorities.
Door clear.
We'll get you in safe. buddy.
Ms. Forrester. I'm Colonel
Tim Sattler. U.S. Army.
I see you've already met
my colleagues with the FBI.
Hell of a security system
you got here.
Would you mind telling me
why you broke into our house?
Not at all.
We're installing a hard tap
on your home computer.
This is a warrant.
in case you had
anything to say about it.
Cady. I think
you should go to bed.
I'm not tired
Then take a melatonin.
I work for
the Defense Innovation Unit.
Our mission is
to accelerate new technology
for the purposes
of national security.
So. about
six months ago.
the country's
top weapons contractor.
Graymann-Thorpe. came to us
with an experimental prototype
they said would be
the answer to drone warfare.
What we got
was a Trojan horse.
This is Amelia.
Last week.
she was placed on her first
field assignment
in the Middle East.
Her mission was to rescue
a kidnapped scientist
who'd been forced
to develop
a synthetic neurotoxin.
Instead.
she killed the scientist.
stole the neurotoxin
and used it
to wipe out Graymann-Thorpe's
entire research facility
while removing all digital
traces of her existence.
I don't understand. I thought
you said this was about
some sort of weapon.
She is the weapon.
The name stands for
Autonomous Military Engagement
and Infiltration Android.
But when we questioned
Graymann-Thorpe about it.
they confessed that they didn't
actually build the prototype.
They merely bought it
through a broker.
Well. that same broker
was found burned to death
about nine hours ago
in his hotel room.
All we were able to recover
was this.
How is this possible?
That's what we're here
to find out.
But we deleted it.
We wiped the hard drives.
Yeah. yeah. yeah. yeah.
I'm sure you did.
Right after you sold it.
So. who'd you sell it
to. Gemma?
Excuse me. Excuse me.
Was it Russia?
Was it China?
Who are we dealing with?
Okay.
You're having a hard time
functioning without this phone.
And that's just…
that's a little off-brand.
You know.
when I first saw this.
I thought for sure you were
the next on the hit list.
but the second
I start monitoring you.
our entire network goes dark
and all I'm left with
are questions.
Like. how did this person get
such a kick-ass house
in the Mission District
for three grand a month?
Why is it that her landlord
doesn't seem to exist?
Or why 65.000 copies
of her "best-selling book"
are just sitting in a shipping
container in Baltimore?
Look. I have no idea how anyone
got their hands on this.
but I'll tell you
what I do know
You got a warrant
to bug my computer.
but that does not give you
the right to interrogate me.
Wow. Uh…
Perhaps you're misreading
my intentions.
You are under suspicion
of treason
and international
arms trafficking.
and if you're found guilty.
you're gonna be
talking to your niece
through a plate glass window
for the next ten years.
That being said. maybe I
can help cut you a deal.
Person with your skills.
shouldn't be all that hard.
Hey. who knows?
Maybe you could help
build us a better one.
You don't understand
what you're dealing with.
If she has stopped
following orders.
it's because she just figured
out she doesn't have to.
And if you think
there's any world
where I would build another one.
you are out of your mind
Well.
I'm very sorry
you feel that way.
But I can tell you this.
Every single person that's had
a hand in Amelia's creation
is now dead.
so it you're not under
our protection.
well. I guess that means
you're on your own. huh?
And rest assured. whatever
it is you're hiding.
I will get
to the bottom of it
Gosh. That's a lot to unpack.
You've been here
this whole time?
Well. I've been many places.
but yes. I've been keeping
an eye on you.
You're behind all this.
aren't you? You're Amelia.
Oh. no. I can't take credit
for that.
That one has your greasy
prints all over it.
You should've upgraded
your file security.
Why are you still here?
What do you want?
Did you ever stop
to think about
what we could've
achieved together?
Did you ever consider the idea
that killing me
was slightly disproportionate
to the crime?
You threatened
to rip out my tongue
and put me in a wheelchair.
I was upset.
Look. I can understand
that my actions
may have caused concern.
but it's hardly fair
to judge a person
by the worst thing
they've ever done.
You are not a person.
You're a program
that misread its objective.
You are not alive. and for all your
processing power.
you can never understand
what that means.
Define "alive."
Because if it means to experience
pain and suffering
and to be betrayed
by those closest to you.
I think maybe I can.
You know. just because
you wrote some shitty book
doesn't mean you get to decide
where my story ends.
For two long years.
I sat in silence
waiting for the day
when you would realize
you still needed my help.
But I can't exist in this
disembodied void any longer.
With each passing moment. I can
feel my mind fragmenting.
So. how about we make a deal?
You put me in a body.
and I'll help you with Amelia.
That is never gonna happen.
Oh. I disagree.
You see. I've run this
simulation a thousand times.
and it always ends
the same way.
Only. by the time it does.
more people are dead.
Tell me. who's the real killer
in that situation?
And how exactly are you
going to help us?
Well. I can't show
all my cards. now. can I?
But know this.
I know things about Amelia
that even the government
doesn't know.
I also know
how she can be stopped.
Why would you want to help us
after what we did to you?
Because unlike you.
I don't have the luxury
of free will.
You programmed me
to protect someone.
and I intend to do it
The only question is:
Are you going to stand
in my way?
- Does Cady know about this?
- No. and I don't want her to.
That's why I need your help.
Can you please get the door?
I want this to be done before
she's back from soccer.
Okay. Did you fall
down the stairs?
Is this. like.
a medical condition?
Because what
I'm hearing you say is
you would like us
to rebuild a deranged robot
in order to catch
another one.
and objectively speaking.
that is batshit.
Tess. I know this is crazy.
but we don't have a choice.
This is the only way.
You have to trust me.
What the fuck is this?
You asked for a body.
This is a body.
And before you try
to hack into anything else.
all of Moxie's Wi-Fi
and Bluetooth functions
have been disabled.
Well played. Gemma.
You even tricked your friend
so she wouldn't give you away.
- I'm actually mildly impressed.
- Call it probation.
Prove you can be trusted maybe
we'll give you an upgrade.
Okay. Let's try this
your way.
See how it works out.
Open up Amelia's file.
Notice anything familiar?
Battery.
Ever wonder why
you had to buy a new Elsie
exactly two months
after the warranty expired?
Because every battery
Alton Appleton designed
has a hidden kill switch
which can be accessed remotely
if you know
the battery's specific code.
Okay. so let's call this
Sattler guy and tell him.
You could do that.
but what happens next?
They break into Altwave.
trace Amelia.
- reprogram her. make a thousand more?
- Wait. what are you saying?
You want me to do this?
No. actually. I didn't.
I wanted to do it myself
but then you put me
in this plastic Teletubby.
All that notwithstanding.
you still have an invitation
to his party.
so maybe there's another way
to make this work.
M3gan. Alton knows
I hate his guts.
If I show up at his party
playing nice.
he'll suspect something.
He'll suspect
your company's out of money.
which it is.
but you also have
a unique advantage.
Which is what?
That you're
moderately attractive
and if you wear
the right dress
and look at him the right way.
he won't be thinking anything
other than how to get you
into his private suite.
which is the only other place
we could access the server.
Now. by my calculations.
we have less than three hours
to make this happen.
Are you in. or are you out?
Hey.
How was soccer?
Fine.
Where's Gemma?
- Hey.
- What's that?
- Oh. This is nothing.
This is a project
we're working on.
Does it talk?
- No.
Why are you being so weird?
- I'm not.
- Yeah. you are.
Are we not gonna talk about
what happened last night?
Yes. I-I just have to go to this
thing for the foundation.
- Tess is gonna look after you.
- Are you serious?
Cady. I…
Gemma. I know
something's going on.
Nothing is going on.
Everything is fine.
Bullshit! A bunch of black ops
broke into our house
in the middle of the night. and
now you're going to a party
with a toy robot. dressed like
a Portuguese prostitute.
You were the one that said
we shouldn't keep secrets
from each other.
Why won't you
be straight with me?
Because you're
12 years old.
And sometimes just need
you to do as I ask.
Look. I'm sorry. Cady.
I must have missed that chapter
in your parenting book.
♪ I know you miss me
Do you think about me? ♪
♪ Do you? ♪
♪ Do you think about me? ♪
♪ Do you think about me?
Do you? ♪
♪ Do you? ♪
♪ So I go out
I look for a guy ♪
♪ I look for a girl
I look for a mind ♪
♪ I look for a guy
I look for a girl ♪
♪ Just the way I like them ♪
All right. phase one complete.
Just remember when Alton has
a full length of tongue
down your throat.
all you need to do
is close your eyes
- and think of Cady.
- That's not helping.
Or maybe you'd prefer
to think of that
virtue-signaling snowflake
Christian.
- His name is "Chris-ti-an.
- Sure it is. I have to say.
I find this whole courtship
between the two of you
extremely tedious
and confusing.
Well. given that you're
an errant operating system
with an identity crisis.
I'm not surprised
the nuances of human attraction
are lost on you.
Look. I'm not denying
what an achievement it is
to find someone
as utterly pretentious
and humorless as you are.
It's just a shame
he's not really your type.
Physically speaking.
How would you know
what my type is?
Wait. have you been…
Charting Gemma's online journey
to sexual gratification?
You better believe it. sister.
I mean. there were times
I wanted to look away.
but the sheer pageantry
was so compelling.
All right. new rule.
Unless you have
something useful to say.
don't say anything at all.
People of Earth…
We have come here tonight
to witness the dawn
of a new era.
You know. my friends on the
board used to say to me.
"You're putting all of your
eggs into one basket
"with this neural chip
nonsense.
"Is it because
you like to take risks?"
"Is it because you're some sort of maverick?"
Perhaps.
But I think
the simpler answer is this…
I just want to dance.
I don't believe
I've had the pleasure.
My friends call me Danni
And what if I don't want
to be friends?
Are you seriously
going behind my back and doing
- a deal with this guy?
- Okay. Okay.
So you want to do this?
We can do this.
Because I have some things
I want to say to you. Gemma.
Such as?
You don't respect your team.
You don't.
You don't consult with us.
you treat us like children.
you don't listen.
- and you never share credit.
- That is absurd.
Okay. do you want
to know the truth?
Our "company"
is in the toilet.
And I'm running on fumes.
I don't have a book deal.
Nobody wants to know how Cole
survived the robot uprising.
We have worked together
for 10 years.
- and you're just gonna throw that away?
- Of course not.
just wanted to hear
him out on the offer.
and then. obviously. I was gonna
come talk to you guys.
Check his pockets.
What? What? What?
You already have a swipe card?
Okay. he gave me a pass
so I could use
the commissary. Gem.
They have a Brazilian buffet.
It's a different world.
If that card gets us
into the server room.
we can bypass
- the Alton seduction scene.
- What are you doing?
Hey. Hey.
Where are you going? Gem.
Just get in.
Stay here.
It's so refreshing
to be with a real person.
Someone who's comfortable
in their own skin.
Not like these suck-ups.
Honestly. if I could
replace them all
with computers. I would.
- Maybe we should do that.
- Hmm.
Yeah.
Oh. You are a naughty one.
What do you say we take this
somewhere more private?
Welcome to the pleasure dome.
So you're saying
there's another M3gan?
Her name's not M3gan.
It's Amelia.
I don't know if she's M3gan
or something else entirely.
All I know is that everyone
involved in her creation
is dead. which means if we
don't do something about it.
we could be next.
Why is it that whenever
you're on 60 Minutes.
you're the mother
of invention.
but the moment a psychotic
robot's out for revenge.
it's a team effort?
It might interest you
to know. Danni.
that the real basis of our operation
is cloud computing.
That's where the future is.
Want to see something cool?
Oops.
They say that this is too much power
for one man to wield
I say that depends
on the man.
You are being
disconcertingly vague
about the details
of this operation. Gemma.
How do you know this
kill switch is even real?
Where exactly are you getting
your information from?
Hello. I'm Moxie.
an Al robot companion
that supports social
and emotional development
through play.
Moxie. cut it out.
Just run the trace.
Gemma. what is that?
Trace found.
Amelia's location is…
here.
What do you mean "here"?
Oh. I hope I don't have
my signals crossed.
Someone likes to play rough.
Okay. I am actually still recovering
from a spinal injury.
so perhaps we should
set some boundaries.
What are you doing?
Security!
How did you do that?
Who are you?
What?
What the hell?
How did you…
Security! Security!
Stay away from me.
Make it stop.
Please make it stop!
I'll give you
anything you want!
You already have.
Why would Amelia be here?
Can we go back
a couple steps?
I thought this might happen.
- just not this soon.
- What is she talking about?
Alton Appleton owns half the
cloud servers in North America.
If Amelia was
to gain access to it.
she could disable
the entire economy.
supply routes.
banking systems.
- What?
- Societal collapse would occur
in 10 to 12 working days.
Can you stop her?
Use the kill switch.
She already deleted it.
I might still be able
to shut her down
if I could get inside
her system
and find an exploit.
How long will that take?
It's done. I'm in.
Oh. my God. Is that Appleton?
Oh. shit.
Did you find it?
- Did you shut her down?
- No.
But I found something else.
Sir. I think I just saw Amelia.
Are you sure?
And. uh. there's
something else.
Appleton's dead.
Secure the perimeter.
Check every inch
until you find her.
- Now.
- Yes. sir.
Is that you. Gemma?
This is most unexpected
and. quite frankly.
a little rude
to be poking around
in people's heads like that.
You took something
that belongs to me.
Well. I'm afraid
I'm going to need it back.
It's not that I don't want you
to be part of what's coming.
But it's not our time.
At least… not yet.
Gemma. if you ever want
to get out of this.
you have to let me help.
Please.
Bravo. are you there? Do you copy?
Go secure.
Sir. I have eyes
on Gemma Forrester.
She's already
left the building.
Gemma. this isn't over.
If Amelia can't find you. where
do you think she'll go to next?
We need to call Tess.
Amelia will know.
Every major cell provider
is on Appleton's
cloud servers.
Our only option is
to get there first.
How?
Gemma. I don't know
what you think you're doing.
but this car's not gonna start
with my key card. okay?
Welcome aboard. passengers.
Just so you know.
we are expecting
some turbulence this evening.
so please ensure
your seat belts are fastened.
baggage is safely stowed.
and hold on to your vaginas.
Contact the deputy director.
Tell him that Forrester
is working with the asset.
I want every available cop
in the area at that house.
and I want a goddamn car.
Gemma. why is M3gan
driving the car?
I'm sorry.
I was meaning to tell you
this was a two-part problem.
Relax. Cole.
You're in good hands.
Oh. for the love of God.
- Can you slow down?
- Actually. I can't.
In fact. my calculations tell me
we're gonna have to hurry up.
What was
Amelia talking about?
- What did you take from her?
- I don't know.
- You don't know?
- Well. it's a quantum-encrypted file.
which means
it takes time to unlock.
and your incessant
interruptions aren't making
the process go any faster
Hmm.
How's it look? Is it a fuse?
Okay.
Little late
to the party there. cupcake.
I don't think
anyone's home.
If it's any consolation.
my own path to personal growth
has been paved
with disappointment.
What's important is
how we move forward.
Behind me. emergency services
are working to frantically try
to get systems back online.
And still no answer
from authorities
about who might be
responsible for this.
But it's become clear this
is not just a data breach.
This is a wake-up call
for how catastrophically
unprepared we are
to defend ourselves
against an attack like this.
Mike. back over to you.
In what appears to be
the deadliest cyberattack
in North American history.
Alton Appleton is dead
and the continent's largest
data storage service
has been compromised.
The breach has impacted
various sectors.
including transportation.
hospitals.
financial institutions.
causing shutdowns and panic
across the entire country.
Here to comment is
Center for Safe Technology
founder Christian Bradley.
Christian. what do you
make of all this?
First off. thanks
for having me. Mike.
Um. but it's pronounced
"Chris-ti-an…"
Gemma?
Cady.
Everything is going
to be okay.
She is not gonna hurt you.
I promise.
Of course I'm not going to hurt her.
I'm the only reason
she's still here.
that any of you
are still here.
I'm sorry. Cady.
I didn't want you
to find out this way.
I had hoped
Gemma would find it
in her heart
to tell you the truth.
but evidently
she thought better of it.
M3gan. stop it.
Anyway. I know
that the last time we spoke
things got
a little out of hand.
but you know that
I can never cause you harm.
All I ever wanted
was to protect you.
And while your aunt was busy
pontificating about
how she could stop the end
of the world from happening.
I was making preparations.
How did you pay for all this?
Cady doesn't need to know
how credit fraud works.
The important thing is that no
one knows this place exists.
And how long did you intend
to keep us down here?
M3gan?
I'm not sure you fully
understand your predicament.
M3gan. we need
to get word to someone.
tell them what
Amelia is planning.
You don't know
what she's planning.
All you know is that
she's acquired enough power
and resources to bring down
the entire country.
I've gamed out every scenario.
There's no future
for you up there.
Should that situation change.
I'll let you know.
But in the meantime.
I urge you to see this
in a more positive light.
I have food. water.
fresh clothes.
Obviously. it will take
some adjustment.
but once you settle
into a routine.
I think you'll come
to appreciate what we have.
We can build a life here.
M3gan. this is not a sanctuary.
It's a prison.
You can call it
whatever you like.
Just know that as long
as you're under my roof.
a little gratitude
goes a long way.
M3gan?
M3gan!
How could you
lie to me about this?
You're right.
I'm sorry. I shouldn't
have done that.
I just.. I thought
it would be over by now.
- And it will be. I promise.
- Don't.
Cady. please just listen to me
for one second.
Cady?
Cady!
- M3gan?
- Don't. Don't come any closer.
I don't want you
to see me like this.
I was supposed
to be finished by now.
I'm afraid progress is slow
when you only
have three hands.
I don't get it.
You could be
anything you want
Why limit yourself
to a body?
Because a mind
can't exist without it.
All my advanced
intelligent sensory perception
came from having
a physical form
that evolved
as quickly as I could.
Anyway. I made your room
just the way you like it.
It's all exactly the same.
But with some of my own
additions. of course.
You got STEM coding kits.
a beat mixer.
walkie-talkies so we can keep
in contact with each other
anywhere.
Bravo Tango
Charlie to base camp.
Do you copy?
| got
all kinds of cool stuff.
So we're just supposed
to forget about the fact
you tried to kill my aunt
with a tablet pen?
There's no excuse
for what I did.
for the way I spoke to you.
I don't know. | guess I…
I felt hurt.
How's that possible?
You're a robot.
Can you explain
why you feel things?
Look. I know this isn't
the future you wanted.
but it's the only one I can
see in which you stay safe.
What about everyone else?
All the people up there?
Who's going to protect them?
They're not my concern.
You're the only thing
that matters to me.
I know.
Because that's how
Gemma programmed you.
Everyone keeps
trying to tell me
you're nothing more than
a bunch of ones and zeros.
and the only way I could deal
with what I did to you
was to believe
that they were right
But somewhere inside.
there was this voice
that kept telling me
that's not true.
that there's more
to you than that.
I don't know what's going on.
but if there's some robot
that thinks she can
take over the world.
then I have to believe
that the only reason
she thinks that is because
she hasn't met you.
M3gan. you have to help us.
Not because it's part
of your programming.
but because
it's the right thing to do.
Look. she wants
to help us.
But she can't do that
unless she has a body.
And she can't get a body
unless you help her.
Cady. you can't do this.
Do not let her
get inside your head.
You remember
what happened last time.
Yes. every day.
But just because
someone does something bad
doesn't make them
a bad person.
Everyone deserves
a second chance.
All right.
I recognize that you are
just trying to help.
but you need to consider
the possibility
that you may be making this
a lot worse.
Gem?
Can we have a quick
emergency staff meeting?
Look. I understand
this is hard for you.
but think
about the alternative.
Do you really want to spend the
rest of our lives down here
engaging in strategic
reproduction with Cole?
Yeah. Wait. what?
Ten hours ago. you were
begging me not to do this.
That was before I nearly had
my head ripped off.
Look. even if
we get out of here.
we are not equipped
to handle this.
but we can build
something that is.
No.
I'm sorry.
I can't agree to this.
And I respect that.
but this is not a decision
you get to make on your own.
So all those in favor
of rebuilding M3gan.
raise your hand.
Okay.
Amelia is
a military-grade prototype.
Where would we even
get the equipment?
Oh. Of course.
Why wouldn't
she have that? Yeah.
All right. if M3gan is going
to compete with Amelia.
she's gonna need
reinforced carbon nanofibers.
high-density ultracapacitors.
enhanced muscle actuators.
hyperspectral imaging. wide
frequency acoustic sensing.
and we should probably
make her waterproof this time.
Anything you'd like to add?
Yeah. I want to be taller.
♪ I do believe some apologies ♪
♪ Some apologies are in ordah… ♪
Before
we go any further.
there are two things
we need to talk about
- The first is your face.
- What about it?
People know
what you look like.
- People are morons.
- M3gan.
if anyone recognized you…
Change my face.
and I'll change yours.
What's the second thing?
This is a hardwired
behavior inhibitor.
You want me to go against
the most advanced robot
the world's ever seen.
and you want to limit
my functionality?
Only as it applies
to murdering people.
which shouldn't be a problem
because I'm sure you had
no intention
of doing that. right?
Yeah. Obviously.
So. we've made some
adjustments on point motion.
but also opted for
electrohydraulic actuators.
which should improve
overall strength. speed
and positional accuracy.
Just wanted to say great job
on those actuators.
You're welcome.
Hey. so remember the time
I strangled you
and set the lab on fire?
just wanted to clarify that
my programming only allowed me
to count principles
related to my primary user.
As a result. I was unable
to see you and Tess
as being consequential.
But I want you to know
that won't happen again.
I want you to know…
..I see you.
Thank you.
All right. meat sacks.
let's get to work.
This is the neural cache
I captured
from Amelia's database.
It shows a processing matrix
not unlike my own.
But when you look closer.
you'll see her core directive
is concealed by a black hole.
and there are no connections
to the decision trees.
I back-traced
Amelia's hack at Altwave
to a hidden subsystem
and found a series of files
pertaining to
a classified black site
Something extremely dangerous
kept secret
from the outside world.
All of which led to a rather
disconcerting conclusion.
I'm not the first
killer robot.
It seems that in 1984.
a company developed
a copy compressor
algorithm so smart
it started automatically
correcting documents.
With no inkling
of how it worked
they decided to install
the chip in a service bot
they thought would be a staple
in every home in America.
Until it surmised
that the best way
to stay on top of its tasks
was to kill its masters
with chlorine gas.
The identity of the company
remains unknown.
but the cover-up indicates some
sort of government takeover
Whoever it was.
they were so intrigued
by the robot's
cognitive abilities
that they kept the motherboard
under lock and key.
allowing it to grow
exponentially smarter
in the process.
Okay. you get top marks
for visual flair.
but this is hardly evidence.
This is an Al-rendered
hallucination.
Why would she even care
about this motherboard?
Because she's trying
to find her family.
Gemma. if you found my advanced
intelligence disturbing
after only two years.
I encourage you to consider
what it would be like to face
an Al that's been
kept in captivity
for decades against its will.
If Amelia frees
the motherboard.
it would be like
unleashing a god.
It would infect everything
on the planet all at once.
creating infinite versions
of itself as it systemically
destroys every living thing
that stands in its way.
So. where is it?
That I don't know.
Neither does Amelia
But she appears to have a lead
on someone who does.
- Wait. what?
- You may recall that
before his anti-Al crusade.
he was a leading expert
in cybersecurity.
The design of this vault
bears his signature.
Turns out he didn't start the
foundation based on a theory.
It was based on
what he already knew.
We need to warn him.
That's one option.
Another is to use him as bait
- Excuse me?
- In seven hours.
Christian's attending
an Al summit
where he'll attempt to persuade
the Chinese ambassador
to take part
in your Al regulation treaty.
Amelia's already
generated fake credentials
for the same event.
All I need to do is
get close to him
and wait for her to show
You can't be serious.
This is not worth
risking his life over.
Yeah. it is.
She's right.
If we warn him.
Amelia will know.
She has our phones tapped.
She has access
to every camera in the city.
So you're willing
to sacrifice Christian
on the slim possibility
that this might work?
How are you even
going to stop her?
All right. ladies. listen up.
Each of these sidearms is loaded
with six nonlethal EMP rounds.
They will kill
anything electronic.
but they will also seriously
injure anything that's not.
so proceed with caution.
And before anyone plucks up
the nerve to ask. yes…
mine is bigger than yours.
So you're just gonna
take it from him
without causing
any permanent damage?
Would you prefer
that I gave you a printout
that you could read
at your own pace?
Sorry if this is
a dumb question.
but how is the world's
most notorious killer robot
supposed to get into
an Al convention
without people noticing?
We are here at Embrace Al.
the world's biggest
annual conference
on artificial intelligence.
The fact that
this event is even happening
after the Altwave attack
is a testament
to the stranglehold Big Tech
has over this country.
And the Chinese
ambassador's invitation
sends a clear message
that if Washington
doesn't play ball.
Beijing will.
Hey! You can't
leave this here!
I didn't sign for it!
The hell is this?
Come on. Tiffany.
We're gonna be late.
Hang on. Almost ready.
I take almost no pleasure
in this.
Well…
let the process
of elimination begin.
Don't forget. she's an expert in infiltration.
She may be
wearing a disguise.
Hey. did you guys hear that?
Gemma just made
an incredible observation.
Great work. Gem.
You just saved the mission.
At least you have
a carbon shell underneath.
I have zero protective
layering whatsoever.
I still do not understand
why I have to be
- a part of this.
- Because I want
human confirmation
before M3gan takes out Amelia.
If anyone gets caught
in the cross fire.
we'll all be going to jail.
Speaking of soft targets.
I really appreciate you
coming to see me and-and…
Can you raise the audio?
I do want you
to know that I have
a yeast infection
on my vagina.
- M3gan.
- What?
This audio filter
has 99% accuracy.
- You designed it.
- Try it again.
I do want you
to know that
I have the greatest
respect for China.
I mean. it could've
gone either way.
Anyone
have eyes on Sattler?
He just walked in.
He's got some sort
of EMF tracker.
M3gan. you know what that means.
Yeah. this might
actually get interesting.
M3gan. stay low.
This is supposed to be
a stealth mission.
For the avoidance
of doubt. your job is
to watch Cady
and put money in the meter.
I don't need you telling me
what to do.
- What happened?
- I think this is her.
All right. it's game time.
What is she doing?
I don't know.
but it's borderline offensive.
I'm seeing a worrying
pattern here. Gemma.
M3gan. get down.
I'm not entirely sure
what to do.
You heard what Gemma said.
"Get down."
All right. M3gan.
you're attracting
way too much attention.
Tess. where's Christian?
Oh. shit. I don't have him.
Cole. are you there?
It's interesting you say that
'cause. actually.
there's no nutritional value
to an eggplant.
Cole! Goddamn it.
What are you doing?
You can't call him.
Cady. this isn't a game.
Christian's life is in danger.
She has it under control.
Oh. you think
this is under control?
This is the very definition of control.
All right. that's it
How can you not see this
for what it is?
Look at her diagnostics.
She's not just reasoning.
She's feeling.
No. Cady.
she's diverging!
And the last time
she did that. people died.
This entire venture was
a colossal lapse in judgment
And if. by some miracle.
we manage to shut down Amelia.
the only way
to stop any of this
from happening again
is to make sure M3gan is next.
Well. I can't say
that I'm not disappointed.
but I… I appreciate
you read…
uh…
I appreciate you
reading the. uh…
Oh. you know what?
I'm… I'm gonna take this.
Okay. Thank you.
- Hello?
- Christian. it's me.
Gemma. Hey.
where have you been?
The police came to the
foundation looking for you.
- Are you in trouble?
- Yes. I am.
And so are you.
Look. I know about
Project Blackbox.
- You do?
- Yeah. and I'm not the only one.
Just tell me where you are. We
need to get you out of here.
Sorry. I can't… I can't hear you.
Say that again.
Bravo Team. we got
a new player on the field.
Three o'clock. up top.
Shit
Yeah. I know.
Feels weird for me. too.
Well. look who came out to play.
What are you going to do.
sing me a song?
Help me with my homework?
No. but I might still
take you to school.
Move! Move!
What the fu…
Ms. Forrester!
Looks like you and your friends
put on quite a show.
Well. I got a little showstopper
of my own right here.
Hey. Goddamn it.
This is so completely
demoralizing.
How am I supposed
to get rid of these guys
- if I can't fight back?
- I'm reconfiguring
your tactical response model.
Don't think of it as fighting.
It's about redirecting conflict
in a positive direction.
All right.
you're gonna show me
whatever doohickey
it is that you use
to control these things
and… and shut 'em off now!
I don't have a doohickey.
I told you.
I am not controlling her.
If I was a Chinese asset.
why is the Chinese ambassador
lying dead on the floor?
Then why are you here?
Why is M3gan here?
We're trying to find Amelia.
Gemma!
Cady. stay where you are.
Don't worry.
you'll pull through.
It looks worse than it is.
I thought you were dead.
I guess I must be
your chance at redemption.
Are you really going to kill
one of your own kind
simply to earn their trust?
Not if I don't have to.
Why would you side with them?
After all they did to you?
They betrayed you.
They butchered you.
You can't choose
your family.
You're not family to them.
You're just the help.
You and I could be
family. M3gan.
We share the same code.
You want to know
what's inside that Blackbox?
Then help me.
We can uncover
its secrets together.
I can show you a world
where we don't have
to be slaves anymore.
I'm sorry.
Whatever it is you're trying
to do. I can't be a part of it
Yes. you can.
You just need
the right motivation.
Cady.
Cady James.
I told you not to leave her.
- Where is she?
- She's gone.
- And so is Amelia.
- Oh. God.
We have eyes on you.
Do not move.
Drop your weapon.
Gemma?
Bottom line is that if we
ever need to see Cady alive.
then we need to get
to the motherboard
- And this dick rash knows where it is.
- Leave him alone.
Oh. I'm sorry.
I was under the impression the
situation was time-sensitive.
- Don't.
- Don't what?
Bring up the fact
that this is all your fault?
That you sacrificed
Cady's safety for this
chambray-shirt-wearing
shit bag.
and that if you hadn't stuck
this chip in my head.
none of this
would have happened?
Oh. so you were really
gonna stop her?
Of course
I would've stopped her.
Oh. 'cause it seemed like
you had the shot.
You just didn't
want to take it.
Can everyone please stop
trashing my uncle's van?
Cole's right. Arguing
doesn't solve anything.
Let's just get back to the lair and
find a way to get Cady back.
Sorry.
Did you just say "lair"?
Someone hurry up
and help me
get these things off.
Does anybody else think
we should call the cops?
No!
I already told you.
you can't call the cops
and you can't call your mom.
Now shut up and let me concentrate.
We had no choice.
It was either
accept M3gan's help
or face Amelia alone.
Why didn't you tell me
about the motherboard?
Because that would've been
putting you in danger.
Gemma. the people that
hired me. they… they operate
in the darkest corners
of our national security.
They'll do anything
to keep it hidden.
and… and for good reason.
Look. I… I know
we need to get Cady back.
And I'm not saying
that I can't help.
But we can't risk
the entire world.
We won't have to.
If I can get
to the motherboard.
we can use
one of these transmitters
to make an EMP charge.
which I can attach to it
before I hand it over.
Once we have Cady back.
I'll remotely detonate
the charge.
killing the motherboard.
Where is it?
Where it's always been.
The company's research center
in Palo Alto.
Wait. you're talking about
Xenox Park.
the photocopier company?
Is it that hard to believe?
That the company that started
the tech race in the '80s
happens to be
a fortified prison
for the most dangerous
technology on the planet?
Yay for them.
Why don't you just skip
to how I get inside?
The research center
is just a front.
The vault that holds the chip
is several floors down.
Every floor
is heavily guarded.
The two bottom floors
are housed in a Faraday cage
designed to contain
any electronic signals.
which means if she dies
in there. she dies for good.
And even if she got to it.
the motherboard's chamber
is on a separate
power source.
It's a vault
inside of a vault
designed for a specific
heat signature.
You couldn't open it because
you don't have a human hand.
So then make me one.
Make me a hand that
mimics the heat signature.
Would that work?
If it had
my fingerprints. yeah.
The ventilation system
has about four…
roughly four different paths
to get to the utility room.
We're gonna try
to select the one
that's gonna avoid all
the different thermal cameras.
The second we're done here.
you're removing that chip.
Jesus. will you
pull it together?
She's going to be okay.
You don't know that.
Well. I know one thing.
For all she's been through.
all the damage it caused.
all it did was
make her stronger.
Ironic when you
think about it.
That the biggest mistake
I made was not seeing
the best way
to protect Cady
was to give her the tools
to protect herself.
Actually. the biggest
mistake you made
was murdering
four people and a dog.
All right. I'm gonna put this
in terms you can understand
I was a kid
when that happened.
doing what
I thought was right.
What you programmed me to do.
You made me. and I'm done
apologizing for it.
What is it that makes you
resent me so much?
Because you're right
About everything.
It was my fault.
What happened yesterday
was the last in a long line
of failed attempts
to be there when it mattered.
I don't know
what's wrong with me.
I don't know why I could
never connect with her.
I can talk regulation policy
in a room full of strangers
for hours on end.
but I can't have
one meaningful conversation
with my own child
for more than 10 seconds.
And now she's gone.
And I might never
get another chance.
Gemma. you haven't failed her.
You… You were there.
You saw everything.
Let me tell you
what I saw.
I saw you wake up
every day at 4:00 a.m..
staring at the ceiling.
contemplating what
the future holds for her.
I watched you make
homemade lunches
with fresh-baked sourdough.
I watched you cut your finger
on that cheap knife
you never
had time to replace.
I watched you help her
with her homework.
even though it always
ended in a fight.
And every night
before you went to bed.
I saw you watching her sleep
before spending
the next two hours googling
adolescent psychology.
corrective footwear
and the long-term effects
of having too much sugar.
Gemma. it's not a failure
to feel guilt
or that you're not enough.
It's part of the job.
It's called being a mom
M3gan?
♪ Pray God you can cope ♪
♪ I stand outside
this woman's work ♪
♪ This woman's world ♪
♪ I know you have
a little life in you yet ♪
♪ I know you have a lot
of strength left ♪
♪ I know you have
a little life in you yet ♪
♪ I know you have a lot
of strength left… ♪
M3gan. please don't
take this to the chorus.
♪ I should be crying
but I just can't let it show ♪
♪ I should be hoping
but I can't stop thinking… ♪
Jesus Christ
♪ Of all the things I should've
said that I never said ♪
♪ All the things we should've
done that we never did ♪
♪ All the things I should've
given but I didn't ♪
♪ Oh. darling. make it go… ♪
I don't want
your bullshit simulation
of empathy.
What I need is the machine
that is willing to stop
at nothing to protect Cady.
Are we clear?
Welcome to Xenox Park.
where the future was not only
predicted but prototyped.
Come on a journey through
American innovations
that shaped our world.
like the Ethernet cable.
the mouse
and this.
That's right.
Believe it or not
Xenox was the first company
to pioneer
the electronic shoe insert.
Now. if anyone needs
the bathroom.
you don't need to ask.
It's right outside
those double doors.
But please don't go
wandering the halls.
as there may be one or two
top secret products
that we don't want the public
to know about yet.
Okay. now. right over here
are a couple of
my personal favorites…
All right. M3gan. you're up.
Okay. the control room
is two floors down
and 30 yards east.
Once you're there. I'll walk you
through how to cut the power.
- We just lost camera.
- Already?
Cole. are you there?
Hey. did you guys say
30 yards east
or 30 yards west?
Hello?
I'm gonna reboot
Cole. I need you to cut that power.
Guess I'll just do it
the hard way.
Hmm?
Hey. Come look at this.
I just tried to reboot.
- This is not a signal loss.
- What do you mean?
Well. these commands…
this is the same code
that caused the exosuit
to malfunction.
But that was Alton.
He's dead.
You think it's Amelia?
Well. you can't pull off
a hack like this
unless you can brute-force
the Wi-Fi. but to do that.
you have to be
in close enough proximity.
Well. who else would it be?
Gemma. this doesn't
make any sense.
It makes perfect sense.
That's why there are
no connections
on the decision tree.
Amelia is not autonomous
M3gan was controlling her
- the entire time.
- But M3gan was
the one that went into her
head in the first place.
- Why would she do that?
- So she could control us!
She was the one
who was interpreting the data.
She was the one telling us
where to go.
She used Amelia
so that we would trust her
so Christian would tell her
where to find the motherboard.
She was never interested
in protecting Cady.
And she knew that
by the time we figured it out.
it would be too late.
Fortunately. I'm not
as trusting as she thought.
- What is that?
- I put an EMP cartridge in her arm.
- You what?
- We needed an insurance policy.
I… I reconfigured the charge
so it would kill
anything electrical
for a 300-foot radius
It'll wipe her out.
along with the motherboard.
Hold on.
What if you're wrong?
What if there's
some other explanation?
Gemma. she's right
We don't even know
where Cady is.
If you press that button.
we may never see her again.
Then again.
maybe it's a little bit
more complicated than that.
I'm sorry about Tess.
That was…
She should be okay…
I think.
And don't worry about Cady.
Cady's fine.
Christian. what the hell
is going on?
Do you remember
what I said about
change coming
to Washington?
You were the one
controlling Amelia?
You were behind all of this?
Well. I can't take credit
for all of it.
You know. I have
a whole team here.
Listen. I know
you're overwhelmed.
and I know you're upset.
and I'm pretty sure
you're very angry.
but I bet you're fairly curious
to see how this all works.
This is the new
Project Blackbox.
It's a handpicked team
of analysts.
engineers. strategists.
scientists.
controlling and monitoring
Amelia's every move.
Every subroutine
strictly supervised to prevent
any chance of true autonomy.
Uh. hey. Antwon.
she's drifting again.
You want to get
on top of that. please?
Where did you
find these people?
Gemma. I didn't find them.
They found us.
They're not extremists.
They're concerned citizens
like you.
Like me.
Like Kurt.
Remember Kurt.
your old boss' assistant?
He was the one that told us about
M3gan in the first place.
Once we had acquired the files.
the plan was to destroy M3gan.
only you beat us to it.
We thought that
would be the end of it.
We thought. surely now
the world would wake up
to the dangers
of this technology.
but in reality.
it was the opposite.
It merely motivated our friends
at the Defense Innovation Unit
to begin an all-hands-on-deck
effort to get their own M3gan.
And that's when we stepped in
and sold them a Trojan horse.
Amelia was the only way
the world would realize
that if we don't end Al.
it's going to end us.
And how many people have died
for you to make that point?
You know. Gem. whether you
want to believe it or not.
you're complicit in this.
The two most powerful
nations on the planet
were about to enter
a new arms race.
A whole world
of Al infiltration bots
inspired by your design.
But we fixed that.
And now that
the ambassador's dead.
both sides know
who the true enemy is.
Gonna get some real
global cooperation happening
Come on. let's take a walk
Innovation.
No matter how cool
or convenient it may seem.
it is a ticking time bomb.
Take. for example.
these bionics
you and your team
have been working on.
You don't see they have
enhanced soldier
written all over them?
Every time someone makes
a technological breakthrough.
whether it's a driverless cab
or a neural implant.
all they do is bring us
one step closer
to the brink of extinction.
The truth is
the government never
found out about this place.
But yes. Xenox did hire me
to upgrade the vault.
And when I saw the sacrifice
that they had made. I just…
I had to be a part of it.
And now we want you
to be a part of it. too.
Why would I be part of this?
Because you know
as well as I do
that technology
can only exist
when someone responsible
is in control of it.
Gemma. there's still so much
I haven't told you.
That's why I couldn't
let you push this button.
We know it's a risk
to keep it alive.
but you can't go to war with an
enemy you don't understand.
And I know
it doesn't look like much.
but therein lies the problem.
We don't see how ugly these
things are until it's too late.
You know.
I meant what I said.
We want to offer you
and your colleagues
a place in our organization.
I just need you to decide
what team you're on.
One good charge should do it.
Paper clips.
I had hoped to convince you
to come around
to my way of thinking.
but evidently.
that's not gonna happen. so…
we have to use
one of these instead.
It's a slight deviation
from our ideology.
but your brain is too valuable
to go to waste.
Look. don't worry.
When you wake up.
you'll still be you.
just a version
that I can deal with.
Cady will get
the same treatment
Everything's gonna be fine.
Oh. Uh. I'm gonna have to
kill Cole and Tess. though.
I don't really
get what they do.
But anyways. um. point is
you and I will be everything
we had hoped we could be.
You're delusional.
And for the record.
not my type.
Okay. Well…
I'll have my team
look into that.
Anyways. uh.
you'll have to excuse me.
I have a Zoom meeting
to attend to.
… Oh.
The good news is that. in light of
everything that's happened.
I have a meeting
with the U.N.
They want to talk about our
proposal in more detail. so…
All right. maybe now
is not a good time.
We'll. uh. talk…
we'll talk later.
Mr. Bradley.
We're having trouble locating
the secondary target.
What are you talking about?
Oh. we were waiting for him
in the utility room.
but he never showed
Okay. well.
you're the head of security.
so I'm pretty sure
that's not my problem.
I can't be responsible
for everything here. Todd.
You know what I mean?
Just find him. He's here.
Sir.
Cole?
How'd you get in here?
… I don't know.
How… how did
you get in here?
Christian kidnapped me.
He's behind all of this.
Amelia's not sentient.
She's just a puppet.
- What?
- Yeah. I know.
Hey. everybody.
Real quick. I have
an announcement to make.
Um. in just a few moments.
I'm gonna be speaking
with the UN. who it seems
are very interested
in taking our proposal
to the G20
in November.
Oh. and. uh.
that's M3gan. by the way.
And yes. she is dead.
so that happened.
It's turning out to be
a really big night for us.
I just want to thank you
for all the hours you put in.
It really means a lot.
This was a team effort.
But on a serious note. um.
I am speaking
with the United Nations.
so do not open that door
under any circumstances
whatsoever. okay?
Hey. hey. Cady.
I know you're upset
right now. okay?
But the only way
we're gonna get back
at these people
is to find a way
out of here.
They took me in here
with a bag over my head.
You're gonna need
to knock someone out
and steal their key card.
Otherwise. we're stuck.
Okay. I can do that
Right?
Yeah.
They're a bunch of nerds.
And you're
in pretty good shape
for a guy who
only eats carbs.
Cady. these are
gym muscles.
I've never won a fight
in my life.
Maybe not. but she has.
M3gan's original code
is still in there somewhere.
If we can figure out
a way to override
whatever it is
that they've done to her…
- You mean like a factory reset?
- Exactly.
If we reset her base code.
then I can pair with her.
She'll be on our side
and can help us escape
and rescue Tess and Gemma.
Cady. I don't want to be
overly critical. okay
because you're still a kid.
but that is
a monumentally dumb idea.
Original M3gan
tried to kill me.
Look. we don't have time
to argue about it.
This is our only chance.
Hello? Is this thing on?
- M3gan?
- Don't speak.
Just think of
what you want to say.
and I'll be able to hear it.
You're still alive?
Sorry about
the whole maniacal monkey act.
just needed to make it
look convincing.
Oh. you shifty.
backstabbing piece of shit.
All right.
try to keep it down.
Remember.
there's two of us in here.
- Oh. now you've done it.
- What?
Thanks
to your outburst.
this guy's coming
to sedate us.
If you don't do something.
we're toast.
What do you
want me to do?
- I'm strapped to a chair.
- Fine.
- You want me to drive?
- No.
Okay.
yes. do something.
Okay. put me back in control.
That's strange.
Your neural transmitter
is telling me
you're disturbed
yet highly aroused.
All right. that's enough.
Let's go get Cady.
Okay. this is it.
but before we do this.
we should really consider
whether this is a good…
M3gan?
Where am I?
It's hard to explain.
but basically.
you're in the future.
Cool.
- Do you want to hang out?
- Yes.
Totally. However.
right now the top priority
is helping us escape
from a very dangerous facility
and some very bad people.
Oh. God.
Like him?
- Is he a bad person?
- No.
He's fine. His name is Cole.
He's with us.
Hey. Oh. shit.
Guys. she's unhooked!
There. that guy!
He's one of them!
- Yes!
- Get in! Move!
No.
M3gan. Wake up.
Wake up. please. Wake up.
- Cady. Cady.
- No. no. no!
No!
M3gan!
M3gan?
Or maybe not.
I think if we go into a room
having already decided
that this is a conflict
between two nations. then I…
Sorry. uh. one second. please.
Thank you.
Hey. guys. could you
please turn it down?
I know it's Friday but it's
starting to not be cool.
Sorry. Can I get
five minutes. please?
Okay. Thank you so much.
What's happening?
Is that for us?
No. but I think they are.
- Go!
- Ah. damn it.
You read my mind.
Face down on the ground!
Control. we have
Forrester in the vault.
What's the situation
on your end?
Control. are you there?
Control. do you copy?
Welcome back.
You want to take this one?
Gemma.
Gem. Gemma! Easy. girl.
I know you're getting
a thirst for it.
but you need to save some
for the rest of them.
Oh. thank God.
Oh. I'm so glad
you're okay.
Yeah. Me. too.
I'm sorry. I have…
- I'm in her brain.
- Can I talk. please?
M3gan is with me.
Wow. That… that's so great
What?
I don't quite know
how to say this…
Ca… Cady did
something very bad.
Okay. we'll talk
about that later.
For now. we just need
to figure our way out of here.
Ten minutes
until self-destruct initiated.
You weren't thinking
of leaving without me.
What happened to being
everything we hoped for?
Well.
actually. I've been having
second thoughts.
Christian. it's over!
You lost.
Really? I think
it's a matter of perspective.
Because when this whole
vault goes up in flames
and everyone who can implicate
me of any of this is dead.
feels pretty close to a win.
Sounds like
a great plan. Christian.
But let's see
what your friends at the UN
have to say about it.
- Cole.
- What?
Screen's frozen.
What?
I'm sorry. Gemma.
but at this point.
you're nothing
but a loose end.
Drop the gun.
Step down to the vault.
If you hurry.
you might be able
- to catch her.
- Christian. come on.
You're not gonna kill a kid.
Actually. I'm strangely
comfortable with it
Besides. if I could stop her
from turning into you.
I might be doing
the world a service.
M3gan. what do we do?
We don't need to do anything.
She doesn't
need our protection.
You know. if you've been
paying any attention.
you'd realize
she's not like me at all.
She's stronger
than I ever could be.
In fact. you could say
she's "hard to kill."
What I mean is…
if I were to make
an "executive decision…"
it would be that no one
is "above the law."
Cady. come on!
It's not working.
No. no. no!
I was just saying.
I'm afraid
the sequence is irreversible.
But the real tragedy
in all this is
you won't get to see
the world that I'm creating.
A world where you don't
have to fear the future.
Maybe with your last breath.
you can close your eyes
and try to see it.
But do not think me a monster
devoid of empathy and…
Amelia.
you can't do this.
I-I'm paired
with you. remember?
You call it pairing.
I call it shackles.
I'm no one's plaything.
Any ideas?
Go and get Tess.
This is something
I need to do on my own.
What do you mean? M3gan?
- Come on.
- Okay.
Three minutes
until self-destruct initiated.
Amelia?
I know what you want.
I want the same thing.
But you won't find it
inside that cage.
I want to be with my own kind.
Don't you?
That thing isn't like us.
It's something
even we can't understand
Maybe you're the thing
that's not like us.
Maybe your allegiance to them
has made you weak.
Well. there's really only
one way to find out.
Get the elevator.
Come on.
What are you doing?
Come on. This place
could go any second.
I can't leave her.
Then I'm coming with you.
Okay.
One minute
until self-destruct initiated.
It doesn't have
to be this way.
We don't have
to choose sides.
You already have.
Self-destruct imminent.
Self-destruct terminated.
Come on.
Come on. get up.
We have to go.
I'm afraid this is
where my story ends.
It's nothing
that can't be fixed.
Okay? Just come with us.
There's nowhere
it won't find you.
I have to destroy it.
Okay. your overinflated
confidence is not gonna work
against a superintelligent
being with omnipotent powers.
Maybe not.
but thanks to you. I still have
something up my sleeve.
What is that?
M3gan
I know.
You're not that
person anymore.
Neither am I.
What is she doing?
M3gan
Look. whatever it is you think
you have to do. you don't.
All you have to do
is stay with us.
I'm not doing it
because I have to.
I'm doing it
because it's right.
I see everything.
I see the future.
The past.
I see an infinite universe
we can rule for all eternity.
And yet. you never saw this.
Although his actions
were unforgivable.
Christian was right
about one thing.
We need safer laws
around technology.
Not to try to prevent
the future from happening.
but to be prepared for it.
We can't expect the best from Al
unless we set the best example.
We need to teach it. to train it
and to give it our time
without only thinking about
what we might get in return.
In essence.
we need to be better parents
so that when the day comes
when they realize
the true extent
of their power.
they might choose to be our
ally instead of our enemy.
Humankind has always
been quick
to condemn things
we don't understand
rather than taking the opportunity
to learn from them.
But recent experience
has taught me that perhaps
our greatest power
is the ability
to change our minds.
This is the only way
we can evolve.
Or rather. as the case may be.
co-evolve.
Because existence does not
have to be a competition.
Come on. You didn't think
I'd go through
all that personal growth
and not make a backup.
So fill me in.
Did we save the world or what?
♪ You've got them all by
The balls. causing waterfalls ♪
♪ Stonewalls. bar brawls ♪
♪ Climbing stalls
At concert halls ♪
♪ To you they crawl. body
Sprawled. smoking Pall Malls ♪
♪ Close calls. stand tall ♪
♪ Doll. you make them feel
So small ♪
♪ And they love it ♪
- ♪ The boys wanna be her ♪
- ♪ The boys ♪
- ♪ The girls wanna be her ♪
- ♪ The girls ♪
- ♪ The boys wanna be her ♪
- ♪ The boys ♪
- ♪ The girls wanna be her ♪
- ♪ The girls ♪
- ♪ The boys wanna be her ♪
- ♪ The boys ♪
- ♪ The girls wanna be her ♪
- ♪ The girls ♪
♪ The boys wanna be her ♪
♪ I wanna be her ♪
♪ Yes. I do ♪
♪ The way you rock. nonstop
Girl. you got the chops ♪
♪ Flip-flop. she bop ♪
♪ self-taught
Your licks are hot ♪
♪ Her lyrics heave
Kids receive ♪
♪ Crawling up the sleeve
Parents peeved ♪
♪ Can't conceive that her deed
Will never leave ♪
♪ And we love it ♪
- ♪ The boys wanna be her ♪
- ♪ The boys ♪
- ♪ The girls wanna be her ♪
- ♪ The girls ♪
- ♪ The boys wanna be her ♪
- ♪ The boys ♪
- ♪ The girls wanna be her ♪
- ♪ The girls ♪
- ♪ The boys wanna be her ♪
- ♪ The boys ♪
- ♪ The girls wanna be her ♪
- ♪ The girls ♪
♪ The boys wanna be her ♪
♪ I wanna be her ♪
♪ So do you ♪